EDWARD DELADEM KOBLA LAMPOH

dredielam@gmail.com | +233541595366

Summary

Software Engineer with 2 years experience in web application development. Passionate about solving challenging problems with code and building products that make the world a better place. Also an Al enthusiast with significant practical exposure to various deep learning architectures. Check my Github: https://github.com/edielam/

Education

Kwame Nkrumah University Of Science And Technology

Sept 2013 - July 2017

BSc. Biomedical Engineering

• Courses: Programming in C and C++,Object Oriented Programming, Embedded Systems

Skills

Languages: Java, Python, JavaScript, C

Technologies: React.js, Node.js, Flask, PyTorch, SQL, MySQL, Bash, Git, Docker

Professional Experience

ALX Africa/Holberton School(Bootcamp)

Nairobi, KENYA

Software Engineering Trainee

June 2021 - May 2022

- Implemented Algorithms and Data Structures in C
- Working on an AirBnB clone full stack development
- Programming languages C, Python, JavaScript, Bash

Levitech Ghana Ltd.

Accra, GHANA

Software Engineering Lead

Sept 2019 - Aug 2020

- Trained a machine learning model for recommending crops for new farming seasons based on soil health profiles
- Built a web application using python Flask framework for deploying the crop recommender model.

Certificates

IBM Data Science Professional Certificate

IBM/Coursera

- Skills: Data Science, Information Engineering, Artificial Intelligence (AI),
- Machine Learning, Python Programming
- Capstone Project Link: https://medium.com/@edielam/segmentation-and-clustering-of-medical-facilities-in-the-greater-accra-region-of-ghana-3baece0b36d9
- Certificate:
 https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/XM8J2M8XTRXX

Deep Learning Specialization Certificate

Coursera

- Skills: Artificial Neural Network, Convolutional Neural Network, Tensorflow, Recurrent Neural Network, Transformers
- Certificate: https://www.coursera.org/account/accomplishments/specialization/4NW2AZZZK43U

Next Generation Sequencing Bioinformatics

H3ABioNet/Wellcome Connecting

Science

- Introduction to NGS Technologies
- NGS data pre-processing and QC
- Alignment to reference sequences
- Variant calling and annotation
- ChIP-Seq
- RNA-Seq
- Genome assembly